RG 004:045, East Lyme Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
East Lyme Probate Court records
1843-1976
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (East Lyme District)
37.5 cubic feet
Record books, 1843-1976; Probate files, 1843-1943.
RG004_045
1912-004 and 2014-006
Historical Note
East Lyme, New London County, Town established in May 1839, Parent Towns: Lyme and Waterford
The East Lyme Probate District was constituted on July 9, 1841 from the Colchester and New London Probate Districts. The Salem Probate District merged with the East Lyme, Montville, and Old Lyme Probate Districts on January 5, 2011 to create the Region #32 Probate District which serves the municipalities of East Lyme, Montville, Old Lyme, and Salem.
Town of East Lyme, Probate District chronology:
May 1838 - June 1, 1843, New London District
June 2, 1843 - January 4, 2011, East Lyme District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Region #32 District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, 1843-1976. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1843-1943. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Inventory control book, 1843-1943 (coverage). Also known as the Godard Digest, it is a list of probate files transferred to the Connecticut State Library. It was compiled at the Connecticut State Library under the direction of State Librarian George S. Godard.
Arrangement
Record books are numbered from 2-44 although four of the earliest volumes are not numbered. There are two volumes numbered 11, one containing orders and decrees. There are four volumes of bonds numbered 1-4.
Probate files are arranged alphabetically in one series.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance. Note: CSL does not hold any original record books. See Alternate Form Available section for volumes available on microfilm.
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in Accession 1912-004 are represented in this index.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- East Lyme
Places:
East Lyme (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Accession 2014-006, Record books, 1843-1976, is stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
Probate files from 1921-1943 are RESTRICTED as they may contain confidential documents. Tax returns (succession, transfer and estate tax returns and all attachments) from January 1, 1921 and later are confidential per Connecticut General Statutes §12-15. Contact State Archives staff for assistance.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, volumes 1-5, 7, and 9, 1843-1924; probate files, 1843-1915; and inventory control book (Godard Digest) were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 1912-004 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on the following dates (with date span of files): August 14, 1912 (1843-1911); January 8, 1923 (1885-1922); July 22, 1936 (1924-1934); September 11, 1940 (1921-1927); March 27, 1946 (1924-1943). They were interfiled into one alphabetic sequence. The record books in accession 2014-006 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on July 22, 2013.
Container List
- Record books, 1843-1976; 27 cubic feet (52 volumes + 2 miscellaneous items); 2014-006
  - Records, 1843-1858 (Volume unnumbered)
  - Records, 1861-1880 (Volume unnumbered)
  - Journal, 1863-1869 (Volume unnumbered)
  - Records, 1878-1891 (Volume unnumbered)
  - Journal, 1869-1890 (Volume 2)
  - Journal, 1890-1901 (Volume 3)
  - Records, 1891-1896 (Volume 4)
  - Records, 1896-1906 (Volume 5)
  - Journal, 1902-1920 (Volume 6)
  - Records, 1905-1914 (Volume 7)
  - Orders and decrees, 1915-1927 (Volume 8)
  - Records, 1914-1924 (Volume 9)
  - Records, 1924-1931 (Volume 10)
  - Orders and decrees, 1926-1933 (Volume 11)
  - Records, 1930-1935 (Volume 11)
    On spine: "Manuscript"
  - Orders and decrees, 1934-1946 (Volume 12)
  - Records, 1934-1938 (Volume 13)
  - Records, 1938-1941 (Volume 14)
  - Records, 1941-1944 (Volume 15)
  - Records, 1944-1946 (Volume 16)
  - Records, 1946-1949 (Volume 17)
  - Orders and decrees, 1946-1955 (Volume 18)
  - Records, 1949-1951 (Volume 19)
  - Records, 1951-1953 (Volume 20)
  - Records, 1954-1956 (Volume 21)
  - Orders and decrees, 1955-1962 (Volume 22)
  - Records, 1956-1958 (Volume 23)
  - Records, 1958-1961 (Volume 24)
  - Records, 1960-1961 (Volume 25)
  - Records, 1962-1963 (Volume 26)
  - Orders and decrees, 1963-1968 (Volume 27)
  - Records, 1963-1965 (Volume 28)
  - Records, 1965-1966 (Volume 29)
  - Records, 1966-1968 (Volume 30)
  - Records, 1967-1969 (Volume 31)
  - Orders and decrees, 1968-1972 (Volume 32)
  - Records, 1969-1976 (Volume 33)
  - Records, 1970-1971 (Volume 34)
  - Records, 1971-1972 (Volume 35)
  - Records, 1971-1972 (Volume 36)
  - Records, 1973 (Volume 37)
  - Records, 1973 (Volume 38)
  - Records, 1973-1975 (Volume 39)
  - Records, 1972-1975 (Volume 40)
  - Records, 1969-1975 (Volume 41)
  - Records, 1974-1975 (Volume 42)
  - Records, 1973-1975 (Volume 43)
  - Records, 1975-1976 (Volume 45)
  - Bonds, 1881-1916 (Volume 1)
  - Bonds, 1916-1930 (Volume 2)
  - Bonds, 1930-1954 (Volume 3)
  - Bonds, 1954-1971 (Volume 4)
  - Index, unidentified
  - Scrapbook of notices from January 1885 pertaining to probate matter
- Probate files, 1843-1943; 10.5 cubic feet; 1912-004
  - Ackley - Bacon (Drawer 1)
  - Badger - Beckwith, J. (Drawer 2)
  - Beckwith, K. - Bond (Drawer 3)
  - Bohun - Burnage (Drawer 4)
  - Burnham - Caulkins, S. (Drawer 5)
  - Caulkins, T. - Clark, F. (Drawer 6)
  - Clark, G. - Connolly (Drawer 7)
  - Cook - Daniels, S. (Drawer 8)
  - Daniels, T. - Dyur (Drawer 9)
  - Eager - Gates, N. (Drawer 10)
  - Gates, O. - Griswold (Drawer 11)
  - Guilder - Haynes (Drawer 12)
  - Hedden - Huntley, J. (Drawer 13)
  - Huntley, K. - Latham, I. (Drawer 14)
  - Latham, J. - Loomis (Drawer 15)
  - Lord - MacNaughton (Drawer 16)
  - Magioncaldi - Mather (Drawer 17)
  - Mathison - Morgan, F. (Drawer 18)
  - Morgan, G. - Payne, J. (Drawer 19)
  - Payne, K. - Prentice (Drawer 20)
  - Pratt - Richmond (Drawer 21)
  - Rinehart - Rogers, M. (Drawer 22)
  - Rogers, N. - Schaeffler (Drawer 23)
  - Schenkewitz - Smith, B. (Drawer 24)
  - Smith, C. - Smith, S. (Drawer 25)
  - Smith, T. - Steil (Drawer 26)
  - Stockwell - Tinker, J. (Drawer 27)
  - Tinker, K. - Ware (Drawer 28)
  - Warne - Whaley (Drawer 29)
  - Wheeler - Winslow (Drawer 30)
  - Wohforth - Zaboroski; Miscellaneous (Drawer 31)
- Inventory Control Book, 1843-1943; T003073
  Index of the five accessions of probate files now merged into accession 1912-004
  Date span is coverage
  Also known as the Godard Digest